# **Brett Markland-Sanchez**



Brett.MarklandSanchez@gmail.com



(404) 754-1929



linkedin.com/in/brettmarkland-sanchez



https://brettmarkland-sanchez.github.io/

## Summary

Methodical Application Support Professional with 8+ years of combined IT industry experience and knowledge in deploying and supporting computer software, domains, application platforms, and knowledge bases. Graduated from the Army Signal Corps School with some college education and training in programming and web design. Accomplished in working with large enterprises of 1000+ employees using standard tools and frameworks such as ServiceNow, Atlassian Jira, Confluence, and SQL. Refined soft skills and professionalism with a background in legal assistance and white-glove customer service.

## **Experience**



## Application Support Analyst

Georgia Tech Research Institute

Mar 2021 - Present (6 months +)

- Tasked with diagnosing and responding to a variety of requests for over 60 in-house applications to help maintain functionality across nearly all of Georgia Tech Research Institute's labs using a combination of SQL queries and monitoring software.
- Primary responsibilities include managing user access for application platforms, reports, and custom web software portals as well as curating advanced documentation that shows typical problems and their solutions on a granular level within Atlassian Jira and Confluence.
- · Additional challenges with communication are addressed when speaking across multiple departments with team leads and business stakeholders to discuss highly technical concerns with and without the use of technical jargon based on the audience.



## **Application Support Specialist**

Insight Global

Mar 2020 - Mar 2021 (1 year 1 month)

- Providing second-level support to 3000+ internal employees with expert knowledge in enterprise-level application systems including ServiceNow, Jira, Erecruit, eStaff365, proprietary ComTrak, ATLIS, and Tableau Bl.
- Performing complex web application troubleshooting and analysis for escalation through ServiceNow and Jira to identify system bugs and potential enhancements in a SCRUM team environment with 1000+ ServiceNow and 30+ Jira tickets to date.
- · Authoring 3-4 graphic training documents each month to provide a granular look at discovered system issues and establish a knowledgebase of their solutions in ServiceNow.

• Successfully implemented improvements to productivity and documentation to help maintain 90% or better SLA requirements for the ATLIS primary data system which has experienced an increased volume of escalated issues by 774% over the past year since migration.

# Information Technology Specialist

#### **Army National Guard**

Mar 2013 - Feb 2021 (8 years)

- Developed expert proficiency in configuring computer hardware, devices, and software to set up and maintain up to 30+ LAN workstations at a time for employees/soldiers.
- Trained by senior enlisted leadership in managing positions to give training and orders for squads/ teams of 4-10 people when performing network operations and project management.
- Provided high-level support knowledge in network stability and server maintenance as well as best practices for software and security implementation to maintain 95% uptime or better.
- Sustained professionalism in collaboration with soldiers and civilians in high-stress environments such as weapons ranges and field training sites by paying close attention to people's emotional states and body language.

# Hypercare Support

Insight Global

Dec 2019 - Mar 2020 (4 months)

- Trained in pre and post-state deployment technologies with SCRUM Certified Product Owners for hiring, paying, managing, and terming contractors with clients during a company-wide platform software migration.
- Supported internal and external employees with knowledge in enterprise-level application systems including Erecruit, eStaff365, proprietary ComTrak, and ATLIS through the ticketing system ServiceNow with over 200 tickets resolved.
- Maintained daily records of known problems and their solutions with edits and additions to 20+ ServiceNow knowledge base entries.
- Analyzed data tables with thousands of records to pare down the volume of duplicate or erroneous column entries, increasing data integrity and cleanliness by up to 70%.

# GTRI

#### **Closed Room IT Support Co-Op**

Georgia Tech Research Institute

May 2017 - Aug 2017 (4 months)

- Provided technical support to 100+ internal employees through the ticketing system Spiceworks and email-based service requests from employees in high-security Secret clearance level areas.
- Assisted in the reporting and management of recorded software information through Atlassian products Jira and Confluence.

- Performed system imaging, software installation/management, Active Directory, Group Policy implementation, network configuration, and application support.
- Adhered to strict compliance standards when working in Secret security clearance or higher environments to maintain data protection and integrity with a total of 0 security risk incidents over the work period.

#### IT & Legal Assistant

Harris & Bunch, LLC

Jul 2014 - May 2017 (2 years 11 months)

- Created and implemented numerous strategies to attract new clients including mailing lists, search engine optimization, graphic design in advertising, and web page development.
- Provided administrative support and research for civil proceedings along with word processing and editing for form fill-able documents and database entries.
- Conferred with over 20 clients per month and other involved parties to gather and track case information as well as provide case support for clients.
- Compiled documentation ensuring accuracy and detail for legal briefs, responses to opposing counsel, court motions, and trial exhibits.
- Worked to increase the firm's presence and assisted partners with reputation management and branding in local community.



#### Game Guide

Ultimate Escape Game

Aug 2015 - Nov 2016 (1 year 4 months)

- Guided game groups of 3 to 7 people, enticing them with descriptive language regarding any of 6 puzzle rooms available for their enjoyment.
- Maintained customer happiness with forward-thinking strategies focused on filling in clues for various puzzles and resolving customer concerns frequently in under 2 minutes.
- Kept records of customer feedback and recommended service improvements at group meetings.
- Established documents outlining concepts, art, deliverable specifications, game flow charts, and overall content to help keep projects moving and teams working together cohesively.



### Junior Legal Assistant

Harris & Bunch, LLC

May 2010 - Sep 2012 (2 years 5 months)

Assisted with note-taking on case details from client interviews.

Prepared case specific advertisement forms for mail delivery.

Aided in computer and printer repairs as well as network drive mapping and business data management.

#### **Education**



### Kennesaw State University

Bachelor's Degree Program, Software Engineering 2016 - 2018 Kennesaw State University Kennesaw, GA

Software Engineering Degree Program - Partial Completion

Gained membership to Phi Eta Sigma Honor Society for the earning of an honors-level GPA during freshman year.

Earned credit hours in the following job-relevant courses:

- Programming Principles I (4 CH)
- Composition I (3 CH)
- Composition II (3 CH)
- Calculus I (4 CH)
- Technical Document Writing (3 CH)



## **US Army Signal School**

25B IT Specialist, Military Information Systems Technology 2013 - 2014 Military Advanced Individual Training Ft. Gordon, GA

25B IT Specialist MOS Qualification

Earned credit hours in each of the following courses after graduating from the Army AIT program in February 2014:

- CISCO Network Fundamentals (3 CH)
- CISCO Routing Protocols (3 CH)
- IT Essentials I (3 CH)
- IT Essentials II (3 CH)
- Network Administration (3 CH)
- Security+ (3 CH)

# **Skills**

Management • JavaScript • Application Support • SQL • Atlassian Suite • ServiceNow • Express.js • Node.js • Interdepartmental Relations • Web Applications